# Mohammad Iqbal Elham

### **Full Stack WEB DEVELOPER**

+93765181256 | igbal.elham7@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Wellfound/Angellist

#### **SUMMARY**

Adaptable Full Stack web developer who prizes professional standards, clean code, and cross-cultural skills. Proven readiness for remote work and collaborative pair programming. Swift learner with a growth mindset, equipped to tackle diverse challenges. Proficient in Ruby, React, and JavaScript, technologies honed through my experience at Microverse.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap, Tailwind)

Back-End: PostgreSQL, SQLite, Python (Django), Ruby on Rails

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

**Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

#### **EXPERIENCE**

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full Stack Web Developer (Self-Employed)

Remote

Oct 2022 - Present

Demonstrated mastery of intermediate and advanced full-stack development concepts, encompassing Rails, Git, and complex data structures and algorithms challenges. Constructed multiple full-stack projects independently and collaboratively through pair programming.

**Second Hand Bookstore** — This project was mainly created for students to sell the books they have read. Users can create a profile, search for their books, add them to wishlists, and upload them for sale.

- Built with: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, Python (Django)
- Facilitated 30 successful book transactions, serving 12 users. Increased platform engagement by 10%.
- Find the source code here and the live demo here.

**Space Traveler's Hub** — This is a single-page JavaScript project using React and ES6 features that fetch rocket and mission data from the SpaceX <u>rockets</u> and SpaceX <u>missions</u> APIs, and we can reserve or cancel rockets and join or cancel missions.

- Built with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- Enabled 8 rocket reservations and 8 mission participation, resulting in a 15% increase in user interaction.
- Find the <u>source code here</u> and the <u>live demo here</u>.

MICROVERSE Remote

## Mentor (Volunteer)

Dec 2022 - Present

 Mentorship of 4 junior web developers, providing hands-on guidance and technical expertise via comprehensive code reviews.

- Spearheaded improvements in code organization and architectural enhancements, resulting in heightened code quality and system performance.
- Instituted motivational strategies and insights to foster long-term program engagement, consistently guiding and inspiring junior developers to navigate challenges and maintain program longevity.

## **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Dec 2022- Present

### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

#### Kateb University

### Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Aug 2018 - Jul 2022

• A study on the design, development, and analysis of software and hardware used to solve problems in a variety of business, scientific, and social contexts.

# **Extra-Curricular Activities**

# ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)

Feb 2022

Ranked fourth position out of 47 teams.

# Google Developers Student Club (GDSC) at Kateb University

2020 - 2021

- Core Team member.
- Helping students bridge the gap between theory and practice.
- Provided Seminars, Workshops, and mini-courses related to Google's technologies, such as Android Development.

# ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)

2019 - 2021

- Co-organizer and IT Technical.
- Building network topologies.
- Configuring the environment and other related works.

# Languages

- Persian native
- English C2, Fluent
- Pashto Fluent